opsmatters.com 2019-06-30

# Privacy Policy | opsmatters

‘opsmatters’ is a trading name of Gerald Curley

### 1\. Introduction

We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors and service users. This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of our website visitors and service users; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.

By using our website and agreeing to this policy, you consent to our use of cookies in accordance with the terms of this policy.

### 2\. Credit

This document was created using a template from [SEQ Legal](https://seqlegal.com/).

### 3\. How we use your personal data

We may collect, store and use the following kinds of personal information:   
(a) information about your computer and about your visits to and use of this website (including your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths);   
(b) information that you provide to us when registering with our website including your email address;   
(c) information that you provide when completing your profile on our website (including your name and profile pictures);   
(d) information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters (including your name and email address);   
(e) information that you provide to us when using the services on our website, or that is generated in the course of the use of those services (including the timing, frequency and pattern of service use);   
(f) information that you post to our website for publication on the internet (including your user name, your profile pictures and the content of your posts);   
(g) information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us or send through our website (including the communication content and metadata associated with the communication); and   
(h) any other personal information that you choose to send to us. 

Before you disclose to us the personal information of another person, you must obtain that person’s consent to both the disclosure and the processing of that personal information in accordance with the terms of this privacy policy.

### 4\. International data transfers

Information which you provide may be transferred to countries (including the United States, Japan or other countries) which do not have data protection laws equivalent to those in force in the European Economic Area.

In addition, personal information that you submit for publication on the website will be published on the internet and may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use or misuse of such information by others.

You expressly agree to such transfers of personal information.

### 5\. Retaining and deleting personal data

We will take reasonable technical and organisational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information.

We will store all the personal information you provide on our secure (password and firewall-protected) servers.

All electronic transactions entered into via the website will be protected by encryption technology.

You acknowledge that the transmission of information over the internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet.

You are responsible for keeping your password and other login details confidential. We will not ask you for your password (except when you log in to the website).

### 6\. Amendments

We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.

We may notify you of changes to this policy by email.

### 7\. Your rights

You may instruct us to provide you with any personal information we hold about you; provision of such information will be subject to:   
(a) the payment of a fee (currently fixed at GBP 10); and   
(b) the supply of appropriate evidence of your identity (for this purpose, we will usually accept a photocopy of your passport certified by a solicitor or bank plus an original copy of a utility bill showing your current address). 

We may withhold personal information that you request to the extent permitted by law.

You may instruct us at any time not to process your personal information for marketing purposes.

In practice, you will usually either expressly agree in advance to our use of your personal information for marketing purposes, or we will provide you with an opportunity to opt out of the use of your personal information for marketing purposes.

### 8\. About cookies

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

Cookies may be either "persistent" cookies or "session" cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.

Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

### 9\. Cookies that we use

We use cookies for the following purposes:   
(a) authentication - we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website;   
(b) status - we use cookies to help us to determine if you are logged into our website;   
(c) security - we use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally;   
(d) advertising - we use cookies to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you;   
(e) analysis - we use cookies to help us to analyse the use and performance of our website and services; and   
(f) cookie consent - we use cookies to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally. 

### 10\. Cookies used by our service providers

Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website. Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to your website or other websites.

Third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on opsmatters.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on opsmatters.com. Google's use of advertising cookies enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL: <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>.

We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google's privacy policy is available [here](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

We publish Google AdSense interest-based advertisements on our website. These are tailored by Google to reflect your interests. To determine your interests, Google will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the web using cookies.

opsmatters.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. opsmatters.com's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

### 11\. Managing cookies

Users may opt out of personalized advertising by visiting [Ads Settings](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated).

Users may opt out of some third-party vendors’ uses of cookies for personalized advertising by visiting [www.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/).

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:   
(a) https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en (Chrome);   
(b) https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences (Firefox);   
(c) http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/ (Opera);   
(d) https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies (Internet Explorer);   
(e) https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari); and   
(f) https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy (Edge). 

Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites. If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website.

### 12\. Log files

Like many other Web sites, opsmatters.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track users movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

### 13\. Our details

This website is owned and operated by Gerald Curley.

The principal place of business is at 43, Burnham Way, Ealing, London, W13 9YB.

You can contact us:   
(a) by post, to the postal address given above;   
(b) using our website contact form;   
(c) by telephone, on the contact number published on our website from time to time; or   
(d) by email, using the email address published on our website from time to time.
